superyachts.com 2019-06-30

# Privacy Policy | Superyachts.com

1.0 Privacy Policy

Superyachts.com is committed to protecting the privacy of both registered and non-registered Users of Our Site. This document details what information We do and do not collect for all types of Users, what information is and is not stored by superyachts.com, how such information is protected, what We do with it and how You can manage Our utilisation of Your information. 

2.0 Changes to this privacy statement or use of data

As an online business, Superyachts.com may add or change functions, features or services. This may result in periodic changes to this Privacy Policy; however We are committed to protecting the privacy of Your personal information at all times. As a result, please remember to refer back to this Privacy Policy regularly to review any amendments. We will use information in accordance with the privacy policy under which the information was collected. 

3.0 Consent and acceptance of these Privacy Statement terms

By using Our Services, You unconditionally agree to be bound by this Privacy Policy. 

Data collection, usage and how Superyachts.com processes information from Your visits to Our Site, may be used in order to: 

  * Process and send Your requests to the relevant marketing agent. 
  * Allow automated services such as emails and text that You have subscribed to as a Registered User. 
  * Customise the information You receive from us via registration process, and which support any specific requests for information You may make through the use of any of Our features and functionality;
  * Send You information with which You have opted to receive, in the format You have chosen to receive it, which may include but is not limited to a yacht’s particulars and articles of interest.
  * Forward only the information You provide to a specified Marketing Agent. 
  * Improve Our Services and Website. 

4.0 Registered Users & Services 

Although it is possible to browse Our Sites without submitting any personally identifiable information, it may prevent You from benefiting from some of Our products and services We may offer.

By completing an online registration successfully this will enable full use of Our Site's functionality. We save the details You provide and use them to enable us to personalise the service We offer to You. If You choose not to provide certain details this may mean certain services are unable to operate. For example, without a valid mobile number Our Yacht Alert service will be unable to send You a text that a superyacht of interest has suddenly become available. 

4.1 Email, SMS/Texts & Other Service

Registered users can opt in to receive emails or sms/text alert services, or any other communications method Our services may provide. Following registration, We send You a Welcoming email asking You to verify Your password and username.

Unless You specify that You'd prefer not to hear from us, We might also use the e-mail address You provide at registration to contact You for promotional, administrative, or other reasons. You may have these communications terminated. 

If You register with us and use the 'Yacht Alerts' feature to receive notification when new yachts matching Your criteria are available, We record the settings You use and which yacht details have been sent to You.

As a registered user, You are able to save a variety of information to Your account for access at a later date. This includes but is not limited to searches, favourite yachts and news stories of interest and such settings are saved by Us. Such information may be used to personalise Your Superyacht.com experience. 

4.2 Correction/Updating/Unsubscribe facility to Our Website and email / SMS text services

All of Our emails and SMS text offer the facility for You to opt-in or opt-out/unsubscribe at any time. Or You can visit Our Website using Your allocated user name / email address and password to access and update Your preferences. You can stop Our SMS / Text Messaging service anytime by also updating Your preferences.

4.3 Email-A-Friend and Recommendation scheme 

We provide a facility for data such as Yacht particulars to be referred to a friend. We ask You for Your information such as Your friend's name and email address so that Superyachts.com can email the relevant information to them. This information shall not be used for any marketing activities. We may forward information about You, (such as Your name or email) that You have provided Us with from the Registration process or otherwise in such communications You initiate to a party or person that is known to You. Superyachts.com cannot be held responsible in any way whatsoever for any data You supply that may result in those not registered to Superyachts.com receiving information You have requested us to send them on Your behalf. We always recommend seeking the permission before providing a friend's or third party’s email address to any service a Site may offer; Superyachts.com or otherwise. 

5.0 Information Request Forms for All Users

In addition to communication with Registered Users, Our Website provides form facilities for any User, (registered or otherwise) to request information on superyachts from Marketing Agents. Within the 'Yachts For Charter', 'Yachts for Sale' and 'Find Broker' section of the Site, all registered users contact information that has been provided at the time of registration will automatically populate the relevant data fields. Any data not provided by the registered User will have to be manually entered. 

For Non Registered Users, any data provided by You, (such as name, email and telephone numbers) for the purpose of allowing Marketing Agents to contact You may be stored by Us for the sole use of Superyachts.com and its clients and will not be passed onto or sold to any third party. For clarity, this information is only supplied directly to the contact details given to Us by a Marketing Agent and is not supplied via any third party. 

You may occasionally see contests, surveys, and other features of Our Web Site that ask You to provide us with information. When You choose to respond to these requests, the information You offer may be used for several reasons. They may also include providing information to third parties as necessary for prize fulfilment and other aspects of any contest or similar offering. If We are going to use Your personal information for any other purpose, We will notify You of that purpose and give You a chance to opt out before responding to Our survey, contest form, or other request, or give You the option not to respond to or participate in the survey, contest or other request.

6.0 Yacht Particulars On Superyachts.com

Superyachts.com policy is that only those brokers with central management rights awarded to them by yacht owners or operators can market a yacht on Our Site. We believe this policy is important as it helps to preserve the accuracy of the data for yachts available for sale or for charter. We cannot warrant the accuracy of the information displayed about any yacht advertised and You should always check the particulars with the agent concerned before relying on the content of this Site.

If You are the owner of a yacht being displayed for sale or for charter on Our Website, this is because the Marketing Agent You have chosen to use has a contract with us to display the details of Your yacht on Our Website and thereby placed the technical information about Your yacht fully in the public domain. Details held by us about a yacht do not comprise of personal data as defined by the Data Protection Act 1998.

If Your yacht is listed for sale or charter on superyachts.com and You require some or all information to be removed, such a request should be submitted to us via the Marketing Agent linked to Your yacht. If a Marketing Agent proclaims to have the right to market Your yacht when in fact no such rights have been granted or no Marketing Agent is directly linked to Your yacht, please inform us in writing and We shall suspend Your yacht from being advertised for sale or charter until such time that We receive evidence that a Marketing Agent has been granted the appropriate rights to market Your yacht on Your behalf. 

7.0 Security 

Superyachts.com places a great importance on the security of all information associated with Our customers. We have security measures in place to attempt to protect against the loss, misuse and/or alteration of any customer data under Our control. The computers that store the information are kept in a secure facility with restricted physical access and We use secure firewalls and other measures to restrict electronic access. If We are working with third parties We will require them to have in place similar measures to protect Your information.

With regard to Our Websites, We use secure server software (SSL) to encrypt information You input before it is sent to us. While We cannot ensure or guarantee that loss, misuse or alteration of data will not occur, We use Our best efforts to prevent this. All of the information We collect or record is restricted to Our offices. Only employees who need the information to perform a specific job are granted access to personally identifiable information. We will explicitly ask You when We need information to identify You. We may require You to co-operate with Our security checks before We disclose information to You. You can update the personal information that You give us at any time by viewing My Account page once You have successfully logged in.

Your information will not be transferred outside of the European Economic Area and We will retain Your information for a reasonable period or for as long as is required by law.

8.0 Site and Service Updates 

We also send Registered Users Site and Service Announcement updates. Members are not able to un-subscribe from service announcements, which contain important information about the service. We communicate with the User to provide requested services and in regards to issues relating to their account via email or phone.

9.0 Log files/IP addresses 

When You visit Our Website, We may automatically log Your IP address (the unique address which identifies Your computer on the internet), which is automatically recognised by Our Web server. We use IP addresses to help us administer Our Website and may collect broad demographic information for aggregate use. We do not link IP addresses to personally identifiable information. 

10.0 Non-personal information 

We may automatically collect non-personal information about You such as the type of Internet browsers You use or the Site from which You linked to Our Website, and other such information. You cannot be identified from this information and it is only used to assist us in providing an effective service and in developing new features on Our Website. We may from time to time supply third party Sites from which it is possible to link to Our Website with information relating to the number of users linking to Our Website from their sites. You cannot be identified from this information. 

11.0 Use of Cookies 

Cookies are pieces of information that a Website transfers to Your hard drive to store which can sometimes track information about You. Most Web browsers automatically accept cookies, but if You prefer, You can change Your browser to prevent that. However, You may not be able to take full advantage of a Website if You do so. 

Cookies are specific to the server that created them and cannot be accessed by other servers, which means they cannot be used to track Your movements around the Web. Although they do identify a user's computer, cookies do not personally identify customers or passwords. We use cookies to store Your default currency and whether yachts are displayed in meters or in feet according to Your selection.

12.0 Shared information 

Superyachts.com will not share or rent Your personal information to any third parties. 

Superyachts.com may disclose aggregate statistics about our Site, (such as traffic flow, Our Website visitors) in order to describe Our services to prospective partners, advertisers and other reputable third parties and for other lawful purposes, but these statistics will not include personally identifying information, unless required to do so by law. 

Superyachts.com may disclose personal information if required to do so by law or if it believes that such action is necessary to protect and defend the rights, property or personal safety of Superyachts.com, its Website, visitors to the Website and customers of Our Services. We will only sell Your personal information to a third party either as part of a sale of the assets of a Superyachts.com company or having ensured that steps have been taken to ensure that Your privacy rights continue to be protected. In addition, if Our business enters into a joint venture with or is sold to or merged with another business entity, Your information may be disclosed to Our new business partners or owners. 

If We offer or supply a service to You that is provided on Our behalf by a third party, We may have to pass Your information to them in order to deliver the service. By using this Site You consent to us providing Your information to the third parties licensed by us to provide such services. We may also use third parties to provide services on Our behalf which may include processing (but not using themselves) Your information e.g. to complete partial addresses or to augment the information We hold about You. In either case, We will not pass Your data to anyone who is not also registered with the Data Protection Act or is not subject to these or similar provisions in Our contract with them and We will not allow the third party to use Your information commercially without Your consent.

13.0 Links 

This Website contains links to other Sites. Please be aware that We are not responsible for the privacy practices of such other Sites and as such You waive any and all claims against Superyachts.com for any and all issues regarding such links to external Sites. 

We encourage Our users to be aware when they leave Our Site to read the privacy statements of each and every Website that collects personally identifiable information. This privacy statement applies solely to information collected by this Website. In addition, this Privacy Policy only applies to Websites owned and operated by Superyachts.com.

14.0 Information storage

Information, which You submit via Our Website or via telephone, is stored on a computer located in the European Economic Area. This is necessary in order to process the information and to send You any information You have requested. We may transfer information submitted by You to Our other offices worldwide and to reputable third party suppliers, which may be situated outside the European Economic Area. Not all countries outside the EEA have data protection or privacy laws. In addition, if You use Our Services while You are outside the EEA, Your information may be transferred outside the EEA in order to provide You with those Services. 

15.0 Changes to the policy

We may change this policy from time to time as We add new services or features or in response to changes in the law or Our commercial arrangements. Any changes to this policy will be posted on this Site.

16.0 Your Choices?

This Privacy Policy should clarify how any information You share with us might be used. If You feel concerned about any of these uses, You might elect not to participate in certain services, features, or products that We offer. We will never covertly collect personal information about You, so the decision whether or not to share such information and utilize the many features on Our Site is completely up to You. 

**Any question or queries relating to this Privacy Policy should be e-mailed to info@superyachts.com alternatively you may write to:**

Superyachts.com  
Unit 1, Mill Hill Ind Est  
Flower Lane  
London  
NW7 2HU
